Jack Ridley



I'm a recent sound design graduate with a background designing sound for theatre. This creative and technical experience has led me to specialise in software design and implementation.

I have cut my teeth designing audio applications in C++ at university and have continued to self-teach myself through online resources such as Harvard's CS50 course, Ivor Horton's book 'Beginning C++', leetcode.com coding problems, and the many others from videos to language documentation.

I have particularly enjoyed the challenges in programming of taking a big system and abstracting it into smaller functions and classes that can be more easily conceptualised and managed/tested.

I'm now hoping to join a software development team where I can combine my passions for creative design and logical problem solving and launch my career in software development with a company I can grow with.

Technical Skills

- C++ - JUCE framework - Wwise

- Python - DSP - max/MSP and pureData

SQL - Arduino - Unity and Unreal Engine

Experience

[July 2018 - present]

Freelance Sound Designer •

Sound Designer and Composer (2018 – 2021) • <u>'Malama Maki'</u>, <u>'Proud Marys'</u>, and <u>'Church of the Latter Day Sinners'</u> with Stacy Makishi

- Designed sound effects and composed/recorded music to be used in the live performances
- For 'Malama Maki' I programmed the music into a sampler system that I could perform live using a MIDI controller during the performance

Podcast Editor (2018 – 2020) • PyData Manchester Podcast

- PyDataMCR is a community group which focuses on **open-source data tooling**. Episodes covered broad data analysis to in-depth machine-learning.
- Edited audio and composed music

Sound Designer (2019 – 2020) • 'Digging Deep' and 'Who Cares' with Just Add Milk theatre company

- **Designed** sound cues for the plays
- Created QLab files for the productions

Awards:

IBPA Benjamin Franklin Gold Award 2022 | Audiobook: Fiction | 'Brilliant White Peaks' – Narrator and Audio Producer

Education

MSc Sound Design (1st) | University of Edinburgh | 2020 - 2022

BA(Hons) Drama (2:1) | Queen Mary University of London | 2015 – 2018

CS50x (Introduction to Computer Science) | Harvard University via edx.org |

Recent Education Experience:

[2021 – present]

CS50x problem sets and lectures • Harvard University via edx.org

- Introduced me to computer science basics including the languages: C, C++, Python, and SQL
- Allowed me to take my learning of computer science and programming into my own hands alongside my MSc

[Jan 2022 - Sep 2022]

Festival Organiser and Host • Future Flavours of Sound Festival 2022

- Hosted and chaired online events
- Managed **budget**, and **compiled evaluative report** of expenditure
- Managed the festival website using WordPress UI: https://futureflavoursofsoundfestival.com/

[May 2022 - Aug 2022]

Physical Sound Interactions **Research Project** • Solo Project • The University of Edinburgh

- Designed interface software for max/MSP and the LeapMotion hand tracker using **Unity** and **C#**
- Designed software for 11 distinct hand-controlled sound interactions using max/MSP

[Jan 2022 - April 2022]

Mechanical Sounds Audio Plugin • Solo Project • The University of Edinburgh

- Designed and created an audio plugin that used physical modelling principles to create sounds of engines, motors, and fans
- Used solely **C++** to write the plugin, using the **JUCE** framework
- Code can be seen here: https://github.com/ridleyjj/MechanicalModelling_JUCE

Other Skills

- Excellent communication skills
- Enthusiastic team player
- Excellent lateral and creative problem-solving
- Strong presentation skills
- Keen and excited learner